Guide to the H. Elliott McClure Papers, 1947-1989.
McClure, H. Elliott papers
- Series VII: Diaries and Correspondence
  - Correspondence Files
    - Chiefs of Police (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Libra Publishers, January 1992 - April 1993, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Don Heintzelman, 1987, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Fred Hechtel; Jack and Morjory, 1986, 1990, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Cam Folk; Will and Testament, Elliot McClure, 1971-1990 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Kimball Garrett, December 1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Joan Gray (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Nancy Greene, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Joseph Forshaw, Birds International, February 1981- September 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Dinorah, 1975-1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Bob Marks, 1978-1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Gathorne, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Pageant Press, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Pilai Poonswad, 1983-1996 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Pauline Reilly; Marshall Liard, 1983-1991 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Ronald Reuther, 1950-1967, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Arthur Risser, September 1986 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Phillip Round, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Royal Naval Bird Watching Society, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Glenn C. Sanderson, 1963-1990 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - M. Yoshii, 1962-1996 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - D. Ande, White Lotus Corporation, 1974, 1992-1998 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Jack Moyer, 1991-1997 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Niyon Thai (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - David Ogle, 1986-1993 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Arthur Risser; Pilai Poonswad; International Foundation for the Conversation of Birds, 1982-1987 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Robert and Martha Black, 1966-1986 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Kikkana; Jiro; Lane; Wycherly, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - David and Jean Brown, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Murray Bruce, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Yuriko Amaha, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Ralph Buchsbaum, 1978-1993 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - National Audubon Society, June 1997 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Pleasant Valley Water Corporation, 2 January 1985 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - County Science Fair, April 1997 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Aero-plankton Project Related Correspondence, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Comments on the Migration Book and Requests, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Edward Dickinson, December 1992 - July 1994 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Prachuab Kwanyen; Hawkins, January 1983 - February 1988 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Ngarmpit, September 1970 - April 1971 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Jong Kol, November 1973 - February 1977 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - International Council for Bird Preservation, 1981, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Bruce miller, 1 October 1984 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Ken Morrisson, July 1984 - October 1984 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Porntip Angkapreechases, 1963, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Tom Baskett, August 1985 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Ernest P. Edwards, March 1972 - June 1979 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Robert E. Elbel, June 1981 - July 1986 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Canada, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Sarawak, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Taiwan, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Responses to Mourning Dove Ad in Defenders, February 1984 - October 1984 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - England, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence related to MAPS, Travel, Manuscripts etc, 1959-1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence related to IUCN, ICPB and MAPS, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - USA, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Nixon Wilson, February 1964 - October 1972 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Peter Wolcott (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Canada, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (Friends) - XYZ, 1966-1972 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - USA, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - XYZ, 1959, 1967-1978 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Wan-tish; Maruko, December 1968 - March 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Yoshimara Yamashina, December 1972 - October 1979 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence- WYZ, February 1976 - May 1981 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Letters Requesting Reprints, 1976-1995 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Bird Nest Material from Malaya, July 1963 - January 1967 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - British Correspondents, 1954-1955 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - K, 1954-1955, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - L, 1954-1965 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Personal Letters, 1954-1956 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - E, 1954-1974 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - O, 1954-1955, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - F, 1954-1955, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - H, 1954-1955, 1970-1974 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence - G, 1954-1955, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence - M, 1954-1955, 1964-1975 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Somchit; Pom Niyomthai, June 1983 - November 1986 (Box 19, Folder 68)
    - Niphan, April 1971 - September 1981 (Box 19, Folder 69)
    - Wang wan Tsih (Box 19, Folder 70)
    - Jeannette Davis, 159, 1970, 1974, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 71)
    - Katy Buri, 1974-1994 (Box 19, Folder 72)
    - American Correspondents, 1972-1987 (Box 19, Folder 73)
    - Pillai Poonswad I, September 1977 - July 1966 (Box 19, Folder 75)
    - Pillai Poonswad II, June 1977 - October 1988 (Box 19, Folder 76)
    - Avian Air Strikes, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Fred Stone, Burma Philatelic Study Circle, September 1966 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Tony Tindaan, 1975-1995 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - David Wells, 1970-1985 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Richard Setlowe, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Woraphat, 19 July 1966 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Somtrakul, 1968-1971 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Bird Recording Work with Jeffrey Boswall, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence Relating to Bird Banding in Malaya, 1960-1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Phillip Round, August - September 1998 (Box 28, Folder 56)
    - F. O. P Hechtel, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 57)
- Series VIII: Trip/Conference Reports
  - Log of the Trip to Australia, 30 July - 9 October 1974 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - List of Birds in Australia, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence related to the Trip to Australia, August - September 1974 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Twelfth Pacific Science Congress: Agenda and Papers, August 1971 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Trip to Indonesia and Malaya, 1 - 16 May 1971 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - IUCN, ICBF, MAPS Conference, New Delhi: Agenda and Papers, 23 November - 10 December 1969 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - IUCN, ICBF, MAPS Conference, New Delhi: Agenda, 23 November - 10 December 1969 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Trip to Hong Kong, Korea, Japan, Taiwan and the Philippines, 24 August - 11 September 1970 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Field Trips, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Trip to Bogor, Indonesia, 14 - 21 May 1973 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Trip to Kuala Lumpur, 4 - 8 July 1973 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Trip to Australia, 12th Pacific Science Conference, 14 August - 7 September 1971 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - 12th Council for Bird Protection, Tokyo, 24 - 28 May 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Trip to Iran and India, 19 - 30 June 1967 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Trip to Taiwan, 5 - 12 June 1967 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Trip to Australia and Indonesia, 19 January - 17 February 1967 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Diary, 27 May - 15 December 1945 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Diary and Reports, 12 January - 9 March 1946 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Airline Mileage, November 1997 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Trip to Indonesia, Singapore, Malaya, 3 - 27 February 1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Trip to Hong Kong, Japan, Korea, Taiwan, 14 June - 11 July 1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Trip to Australia, 30 July - 9 October 1974 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Trip to India, 23 - 26 January 1969 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Trip to Malaya, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Hong Kong - Taipei Trip, 13 - 23 September 1964 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - World Recreation Congress, Osaka-Kyoto, 1 - 8 October 1964 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Trip to Korea, 10 - 14 December 1963 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - World Trip, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Taiwan, Hong Kong and Bangkok Trip, 26 February - 15 March 1964 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Trip to Korea, 6 - 9 April 1964 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Japan - Field Trips, 27 April 1964 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Trip to Malaya, Thailand and Philippines, 22 January - 13 February 1964 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Trip to Bangkok, Malaya, Hong Kong, 27 July - 16 August 1964 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Trip to Korea, 10 - 15 July 1964 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Trip to Taiwan, Manilla and Leyte, 20 May - 14 June 1964 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - World Trip, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Trip to Calcutta, 25 - 28 September 1968 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Trip to Bangkok, 30 May - 3 June 1966 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Pacific Science Congress, Tokyo, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Trip to the States, 20 January - 23 March 1966 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Trip to Iwo Jima, 7 - 8 April 1966 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Korea, 22 - 26 September 1965 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Trip to South East Asia, 26 July - 8 September 1965 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Karuizawa, Japan, 10 - 11 June 1965 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Trip to Yamaguchi and Toyooka, Japan, 10 - 15 April 1965 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Trip to Philippines, Borneo, Malaya and Thailand, 1 February - 7 March 1965 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Trip to India, 10 - 14 October 1966 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Trip to Malaya and Borneo, 16 October - 1 November 1966 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Trip to Malaysia, 9 - 21 June 1968 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Trip to East Pakistan, 15 - 19 March 1968 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Trip to Indonesia, Malaya, 28 January - 10 February 1968 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Trip to India, 15 - 27 December 1967 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Trip to Korea and Japan, 16 July - 2 August 1967 (Box 26, Folder 28)
- Series IX: Organizations - Defenders of Wildlife
  - Board of Directors Meeting, April 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Trapping Information Package, November 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Board Members' Resumes, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, May 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: John W. Grandy, November 1978 - June 1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, April 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Staff Reports, Administrative Reports, June 1983 - December 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Staff Reports, Administrative Reports, Budget Proposals, February 1984 - January 1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Issues Reports, Administrative Reports, November 1984 - January 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Research Committee Report, April 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Defenders of Wildlife: Five year Plan, 1982-1986, 15 April 1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Maine Chapter: Proposed First Year Chapter Objectives, 30 June 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mourning-Dove Hunting Issue, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, April 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Financial Statements and Independent Auditors' Report, 31 December 1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Strategy Planning: Staff Task Force Assignments, 19 May 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Quarterly, Annual and Audit Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - National Wildilfe Refuge System, Action Fund Proposal, April 1980 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors Meeting at Pacific Grove, December 1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Series X: Migratory Animals Pathological Survey
  - Certificate: Banded Bird Reporting (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence: Colonel Watton, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence: K. C. Emerson, January 1962 - June 1970 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Grants, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Species Record, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Conference, New Delhi, 24 November - 10 December 1969 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Photographs and Biographies: Personnel (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Grants, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Grants, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Grants, 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Drafts and Correspondence related to ASRCT Grants, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - SEATO, 1968-1970 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notes, Papers, Correspondence: Project Material (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Project Material (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Conference, Tokyo, 20 August - 8 September 1966 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Conference, Khao Yai I, 18 - 24 August 1968 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Conference, Khao Yai II, 18 - 24 August 1968 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Conference, Khao Yai III, 18 - 24 August 1968 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Conference, Kuala Lumpur, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Annual Meeting, Philippines, 25 October - 16 November 1967 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Banding Kits, Holding Cages, Other Miscellany (Box 28, Folder 63)
  - Biographical Sketches of Proffesional Staff (Box 28, Folder 64)
- Series XI: Manuscripts and Drafts
  - Avian Disease and Parasites: Best Early Papers, 1950-1960 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Avian Disease and Parasites: Best Early Papers (Contd.), 1950-1960 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Assorted Publications - H. Elliot McLure, 1963-1978 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - White Lady of the Caverns, May 1977 - May 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Singers are Heard, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - House Swallows in Malaya: Summary of Repeats, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Colated Ages of Asian Birds (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Phoebes in Central Nebraska (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - A Wave of Birds, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - The Population Density of Birds in Selected Habitats of Western Malaysia, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Manuscript and Data: Wildlife Over-Harvesting in South East Asia, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Data: Wildlife Over-Harvesting in South East Asia, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Data: Wildlife Over-Harvesting in South East Asia, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Avian Bionomics in Malaya: The Avifauna Above 5000 Feet Altitude at Mt. Brinchang, Pahang, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Three Notes on Thai Birds, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Birds of Brinchang, 1958-1962 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Nesting of the White Whiskered Tree Swift in Malaya, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Review of "The Birds of the Malay Peninsula", 1977 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - The Incandescent Roosts of Swallows, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 25 Years of Bird Watching at Mt. Takao, near Tokyo, Japan, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - The Wilted Forest, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Origins of City Birds; The Small Town as an Ecological Entity, 1966-1974, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Hashioki - A Japanese Art Form, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - The Tree, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Bio-diversity versus Bio-perversity (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Haematazoa in the Birds of Asia (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Those Neglected Babblers (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Roosting and nesting of the Chimney Swift in East Texas, by Wan-tsih H. Chao, May 1970 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Ping River Cavalcade (Mae Ping River Studies), 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Batu Cave Manuscripts
    - Manuscripts, Figures, Reprints: Fauna of the Dark Cave; Animals New to Science in the Dark Cave of Batu Caves (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Fauna of the Dark Cave (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Fauna of the Dark Cave, Raffles Version (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Fauna of the Dark Cave, Draft (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Microcosms of Batu Cave, Copy (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Fauna of the Dark Cave, Original Draft (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Fauna of the Dark Cave, Copies (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Fauna of the Dark Cave, Copy (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Fauna of the Dark Cave, Ecology Version (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript and Correspondence: Recent Changes in Male House Finch Plumage Variation, by Sherie Zahn, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - House Finch Parasites and Color, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Index for "Migration" (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Avian Malaria in the Tropical Subregion (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Mt. Takao Birds (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Thornbill Studies, Pilai Poonswad et al (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Manuscripts and Notes: Summaries of Japan Studies, 1950-1954 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Comparative Studies of Animal Populations in the Development of a Beech-Maple Forest, 1933-1936 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - The Development of a Climax Forest in Central Illinois, 1932-1935 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Seasonal Succession in a Forest Along the Illinois River (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Seasonal Observations of Invertebrates at the Stripmine Area, Illinois (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Development of a Climax Forest upon a Flood Plain, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Evidence of Periodicity among the Arthropods of the Dipterocarp Forest Canopy in Malaya (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Some Arthropods of the Dipterocarp Forest Canopy in Malaya, 1960-1963 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Arthropods Manuscript to Malayan Nature Journal, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - A Collection of Ectoparasites from Malayan Birds, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript of Aero-plankton Studies, 1934-1936 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Aero-plankton to Bird Watchers, 1986, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Aero-plankton Studies, 1934-1936 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Bark Fauna, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Manuscripts and Notes: Nest Parasites (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Status of Birds of Japan in 1955, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Arthropod movements and the Chameleon (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Assorted manuscripts and Notes, 1935-1939 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Effects of Cold Weather on a Rainforest and its Inhabitants, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Notes and Manuscript: Evidence of Periodicity among the Arthropods of the Dipterocarp Forest Canopy in Malaya, 1960-1963 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Two Tropical Forests and Their Birds (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Manuscript Clearance, 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Revision: Migration and Survival of the Birds of Asia
    - Pages 1-69: Foreword; Part 1 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Pages 70-155: Part 2, Maps and its Fifth Year (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Pages 59-306: Discussion of Movements by Species (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Pages 155-189: Part 3, Discussion of movement by Species (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Pages 191-216 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Pages 217-256 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Pages 257-271 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Pages 272-292 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Pages 340-399 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts and Negatives: Bird Residency in Japan and Malaya, 1957-1962 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - English Vernacular names of the Birds of the Malayan Subregion; Avian Bionomics in Malaya 3 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript and Photographs: Avian Bionomics of Malaya 3 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript and Photographs: The Composition of Mixed Species Flocks in Lowland and Sub-montane Forests of Malaya (Avian Bionomics in Malaya 3) (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Composition of Mixed Species Flocks (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Sources of Migration Patterns of the Birds of Asia (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Migration Patterns in Eastern Asia (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Bio-diversity vs. Bio-perversity (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Birds and Drought in South East Asia in 1983, 1983, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Avifaunal Distribution of Birds in Eastern Asia from Singapore to Hokkaido in the Spring of 1955, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Avifaunal Distribution of Birds in Eastern Asia, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Survival Among Birds of Eastern and South East Asia; Bird banding Manual Identification Guide to Japanese Birds (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Manuscripts on Japanese Birds, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Manuscript and Banding Lists: Avian Populations Near Tokyo, 1951-1955 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Manuscript on Japanese Birds, Banding Lists, Photographs of Netting habitats, Maps of Shin Hama, 1951-1957 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Kingfishers - Gems of the Forest, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Pitta, The Jewel Thrushes, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - The Sale of Birds at the Bangkok "Sunday Market"; Khao Yai, A National Park for Thaliand? (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - A Quarter of a Century, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Published Manuscripts, 1956, 1963-1965 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Birds as Discriminators of Disease (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Some Observations of primates in the Climax Diptocarp Forest near Kuala Lumpur, Malaya (Box 17, Folder 12B)
  - Manuscripts, Photographs, Plates: Aenoplex carpocarsae cushman, A Parasite of the Codling moth (Carpocacapsa pomonella linne); Little bugs to Bite 'Em (Box 17, Folder 12C)
  - Annual Report, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Annual Report, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Annual Report, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Avain Crisis in South East Asia (Box 21, Folder 111)
  - Food Webs in a Tropical Cave, 1978-1980 (Box 21, Folder 112)
  - Manuscript and Banding Lists: Two Tropical Rainforests and Their Birds, 1958-1960, 1967-1970 (Box 21, Folder 113)
  - Assorted Published Manuscripts, 1957-1969 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - The Effect of Fruiting Fig on Bird Density in a Forest (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - The Effect of Fruiting Fig on a Forest Biomass (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Wat Phai Lom Original Manuscript, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Nesting of birds in a Coconut-Mangrove Habitat off the West Coast of Western Malaysia, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - The Conservation of Forest; Mixed Feeding Flock (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - An Estimation of a Bird Population in the primary Forest of Selangor, Malaysia (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Manuscripts, Photographs and Banding Lists: A Summer Bird Population in Japan, 1950-1955 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Manuscripts and Photographs: Their Paths Mingle: Bird Migration in East Asia, 1977-1978 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Birds of Hokkaido, 1955-1957 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - The Wonderful Nature of Sounds (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Birds of the Konto Plain a Generation Ago, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Bird Ringing - Avocation and Hobby (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - An Unusual Migration Wave at Tokyo, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Manuscript and Banding Lists: Avifaunal Distribution in Eastern Asia from Singapore to Hokkaido in the Spring of 1955, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Bird Ringing in Asia; Bird Migration in the Far East and its Zoogeographical Implications (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Primates in the Dipterocarp Forest (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Manuscripts Under Construction (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Avian Bionomics of Malaya; Effect of Tree Removal on a Local Population (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Manuscripts and Worksheets: Bird Movements in Subang (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Sex and Age Ratios of Japanese Birds; Methods of Bird Netting Applicable to Some Wildlife Management Problems (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Manuscript and Photographs: Methods of Bird Netting in Japan Applicable to Some Wildlife Management Problems (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Unfinished Papers (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Garden Birds of Kuala Lumpur, 1958-1960 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Some Bird "Rarities" (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Birds and Encephalitis in Japan (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Review: The Haemaphyalis Ticks of Birds, by Harry Hoogstraal and Hilda Wassef, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Japanese B Encephalitis in Wild Birds, Japan, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Current Concepts of the Role of Migratory Birds in the Dispersion of Zoonoses (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Seriological Survey of Birds in Japan (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Arrival of Continental Migrants in Japan, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Survival Among the Birds of Eastern and South Eastern Asia, 1982-1984 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Some Aspects of Bird Migration in Asia (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Voices of Khao Yai (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - The Wilted Forest (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Dispersal of Egrets on the Konto Plain (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript, Figures, Photographs and Notes: Some Flowering and Fruiting in the Canopy (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Some Problems Concerning Endangered Birds in South East Asia (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts, Figures, Notes and Slides: Some Flowering and Fruiting in the Forest Canopy (Box 23, Folder 18)